RG 074:069, Peter Colt Family Genealogical Papers
Connecticut State Library
Peter Colt Family genealogical papers
1856-2010
Connecticut State Library
Colt family
1 envelope
Genealogical material on the Peter Colt Family.
RG074_069
2011-035
Scope and Content
Contains genealogical material on the Peter Colt Family. Of note is the typescript of writings of Catherine Wadsworth Colt (Mrs. Aaron S. Pennington), most of which she copied in 1856 from originals, that includes an autobiographical sketch written by Peter Colt in 1823, the year before he died.
Related Material
Colt family letters, consisting of correspondence of Peter Colt and his family while in Connecticut, New Jersey, New York and Pennsylvania, 1775-1877. 68 documents [CSL call number StLib Archives 920 C73]
Colt Family Papers, 1777-1913, Rutgers University Library, Special Collections/University Archives, New Brunswick, N.J.
Index Terms
Alternate Authors:
Cromwell, Margaret Oliver, 1898-2002; Josephs, Peter Colt, 1939-; Pennington, Catherine, 1835-1869
Subjects:
Colt family; Colt, Peter, 1736-1824 -- Family; Colt, Roswell L. (Roswell Lyman), 1779-1856; Connecticut -- Genealogy; Josephs, Devereux Colt, 1893-1977; New Jersey -- Genealogy; New York -- Genealogy
Restrictions on Access
These papers are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Acquisition Information
These documents were given to the Connecticut State Library by Peter Colt Josephs (1939- ) on October 21, 2010.
Custodial History
These documents were passed from Lyman Colt Josephs I (1853-1942) to his daughter Mary Josephs Fowler (1893-1980) to her executrix and second cousin Margaret Oliver Dunn Cromwell (1898-2002) to Mary Josephs Fowler's nephew Peter Colt Josephs (1939- ). Peter Colt Josephs is a second cousin once removed to Margaret Oliver Dunn Cromwell.
Container List
- Papers, 1856-2010
  - Writings of Catherine Wadsworth Colt (Mrs. Aaron S. Pennington), 1856, undated; typescript
    Contents: "A Chronology of the Colt Family", 2 leaves; "A Little Scrap of Colt Genealogy given to me by Mrs. Selden, in Troy, 1856", 2 leaves; "An account of the family of of COLT written by Peter Colt, Esq. in the year A.D. 1799, copied by his grandaughter, Catherine...", 5 leaves; "Another account of the family very similar to the above written by my grandfather in Paterson, N. Jersey, A.D. 1818. Cathe. Pennington, Jany 15th, 1856", 8 leaves; "An Account of my GRANDFATHER'S LIFE written by himself the year before his death, copied from the original in the possession of my father Jany. 22d. A.D. 1856. Cather. Pennington." 17 leaves
    The date of the typescript is not known
    Includes an inventory compiled by Peter Colt Josephs, March 1983.
  - Peter Colt's history of the Colt Family, undated; 13 pages, photocopy
    Transcription of the original by Peter Colt written in 1817
    Verso of last page contains a note on the S.U.M. (Society for the Promotion of Useful Manufactures)
  - Copy of papers concerning the Colt and Lyman Families, undated; 5 leaves, photocopy
  - Descendants of Peter Colt and Sarah Lyman, undated; 1 leaf, photocopy
    From a 15 page unpublished manuscript by Lyman Colt Josephs II, compiled in 1962 at Bel Air, Maryland. The entire manuscript consists of 9 pages of text and 6 unpaginated pages of genealogy. This is the fourth unpaginated page.
    Annotated by Peter Colt Josephs
  - Peter Colt descendants / compiled by Peter Colt Josephs, 2010; 1 leaf, manuscript
  - Descent of Robert Emmet Sherwood - Colt Family, American playwright and biographer / compiled by Peter Colt Josephs, undated; 2 leaves, manuscript
    Robert Emmet Sherwood was awarded the Pulitzer Prize four times.
  - Colt Family lines of descent / compiled by Peter Colt Josephs, 2005
  - Chronology, undated; 3 leaves, photocopy
  - Roswell Lyman Colt at age 53 by Thomas Sully, 1832; photocopy
  - Roswell Lyman Colt letter to his children, 1856 August 2; 2 leaves, photocopy
  - Obituary of Roswell L. Colt, 1856; 1 leaf, photocopy
    Annotated by Margaret Oliver Cromwell (MOC)
    There is also a photocopy of the obituary of Margaret Cromwell
  - "Devereux C. Josephs: Philanthropy, Public Service and Profits", 1958 January 18; photocopy
    Article from Saturday Review, "SR's Businessman of the Year". The issue has a photo portrait of Devereux C. Josephs on the cover
    There are twin portraits of Devereux C. Josephs hanging at New York Life and at the Harvard Club of New York
  - Devereaux Colt Josephs obituary and tribute, 1977; 2 items, photocopies
    Obituary is from the New York Times and is annotated by Peter Colt Josephs
    Tribute is by Ethan Allen Hitchcock, Chairman of the WNET/13 Board and was printed in the WNET/13 program guide, The Dial in February, 1977
  - The Colt Family in Paterson / Researched and assembled by the Jerseymen of Paterson Catholic Regional High School, circa 1977; 4 leaves, photocopy
    Contains writings by Peter Colt Josephs
  - Peter Colt Josephs letters, 1982-1983, 2010; 4 items
    Reply letters from the Library of Congress (1982) and the Passaic County Historical Society (1983) to Josephs informing on the location of Peter Colt Family material. Letters from Rutgers University (2010) to Josephs acknowledging receipt of a photocopy of the original typescript of three autobiographies of Peter Colt as transcribed by his granddaughter Catherine Wadsworth Colt (Mrs. Aaron S. Pennington) in 1856.